Guide to the Susan Christopherson papers, circa 1983-2016.
Christopherson, Susan papers,
- Series II. Research
  - Hatch Project Data, etc., 2003-2005 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Shale Gas Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
      Includes radio host Susan Arbetter-related materials NRC Workshop notes-correspondence with Jacob McNally, reaction to Broome County plan, notes on New Headwater's Study, etc.
    - Citizen Science notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
      Four pages of notes on citizen science and new forms of expertise in energy, which appears to have been a possible comparative project
    - NYS ED$ PANEL, Undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
      Three pages of notes on a panel about education spending in NY State
    - UNC BOOK PROPOSAL, 2014-2015 (Box 6, Folder 49)
      Contains notes on the proposal for a book about shale gas that was submitted to the University of North Carolina Press by SMC and Ned Rightor. There are many versions of reaction to the reviews as well as correspondence with their editor, Joseph Parsons, a draft contract with comments, a later memo on how the book is evolving from a primer to a set of essays, and related materials.
    - Incentives Chapter One, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 50)
      Various short notes and a few popular press articles
    - Incentives Chapter Three, 2014-2015 (Box 6, Folder 51)
      Notes, chapter synopsis, a memo about next steps, and other materials for SMC and Ned Rightor's book on insentives. Despite folder title, there are also some hand-written notes about the second chapter of the book as well.
    - Chapter Four Measures, 2011-11-01 (Box 6, Folder 52)
      Contains only an e-mail from Christopher Smith about trends in non-employer establishments during the 2000s in the film industry
    - Shale-Related, 2010-2012 (Box 6, Folder 53)
      A variety of reports related to energy as well as correspondence with new research assistant Sam Scoppettone
    - New Heinz Proposal 2013, 2013-2014 (Box 6, Folder 54)
      Notes and memos related to Heinz-funded research on economic impact of fracking and possibility of tourism as alternative local economic development strategy; Includes a budget with SMC salary noted
    - Heinz Job Project, 2013-2014 (Box 6, Folder 55)
      Data, charts, and other materials, including meeting notes, memos, and completed proposal to Heinz
    - Heinz Report, 2016-03-29-2016-04-04 (Box 6, Folder 56)
      A memo requesting the final Heinz report and SMC's cover page for the final report
    - Manu[facuturing] and Finance, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 57)
      Notes and a preliminary paper (3 days before the 12/14/2013 presentation) for a talk at a workshop on financialization of Society at Trinity College, Dublin. The talk is called "How Does Financialization Affrect Manufacturing Investment? Preliminary Evidence for the US and UK"
    - GUNI HE PPR, 2015 (Box 6, Folder 58)
      Correspondence related to an invited paper that was to be written for the 6th GUNi World Report in Higher Education. The paper was not published. Also contains notes for the "Erkner talk"
    - Birmingham Talk, 2015 (Box 6, Folder 59)
      Notes and related materials for a talk SMC gave at the second Global Value Chains in Europe Network two-day workshop entitled "Bariers to Re-shoring Manufacturing"
    - Manufacturing PPR [paper], 2014 (Box 6, Folder 60)
      Notes for a paper on manufacturing that was intended for Policy Journal
    - GRT LAKES OIL TRNSPRT, Undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
      A few notes, clearly not the central repository of work on this topic.
    - Large Firms and Regions, Undated (Box 6, Folder 62)
      A few notes about changes in corporate attitudes regarding their obligations to regions
    - Regions Book Proposal, Undated (Box 6, Folder 63)
      Many notes and related materials for the regions book (with Jennifer Clark), including a series description of David Angel's series for Routledge. Notes related to article including correspondence with Jennifer Clark (then at Cornell)
    - U.S. Firms in Germany: Data, 1991-1993-05-21 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Contains note cards detailing some U.S. firms working in Germany along with the sources of that information
    - U.S. Firms in Germany: Sources Articles, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Contain materials related to companies in Germany
    - Germany: Rules as Resources, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Contains notes and a paper entitled Complicating Assumptions: Rules as Resources in Anglo-American and German Investment Decisions that was presented at a conference on European integration in Berlin, July 22-25, 1993
    - Fragemented Bargaining Power, 1993-02 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      A 1991 version and 1993 draft paper with edits entitled The Path to Fragmented Bargaining Power: Industrial Relations in Entertainment Media
    - Innovative Economic Development Strategies, 1995-07-11 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      A proposal for the U.S. Department of Agriculture to document efforts among economic development agencies that promote "alternatives to inter-juridictional competition among state and local officials"
    - Book with Linda McDowell, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Notes for a book with English geographer Linda McDowell, along series description/proposal for “Reshaping Human Geography: A Major New Introductory Series,” edited by Stuart Corbridge, Ron Martin and Linda McDowell. Within the series proposal there are seven books described, only two of which have authors assigned. One is ‘Work, Welfare, and Community,’ to be authored by Susan Christopherson and Linda McDowell. There’s a one paragraph description of the work, which will “focus..on the geography of labour and social reproduction.” My guess is that this is from the early-1990s as it say you hope to publish all series titles by mid-1993 at the latest.
    - Women and Industrial Change Book Prospectus, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
      An outline for a book entitled: 'Women's Role in Economic Transformation: The Contradiction of Female Wage Labor' accompanied by some notes and a copy of a 3-page proposal abstract from when SMC worked at the U.S.-Mexico Study Center. This folder was in with the other folders in the 'Reshaping U Geography Book with Linda ' hanging folder.
    - Women in Geography Paper, 1989-11 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      An unpublished paper, written with Margaret Fitzsimmons (then at UCLA), entitled 'Women in Geography: Limits to Progress,' that was submitted to The Professional Geographer in November, 1989, and some related pieces.
    - Market Rules: Talk, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Contains presentation notes, a full script, and overheads for talks relating to SMC 1993 paper 'Market Rules'
    - DC Talk-DOL: Child and Ecare, 1997-04-12-1997-12-12 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      Notes and executive summary for a talk entitled 'Filling the Growing Need for Childcare and Elderly Care' that was given at the Department of Labor, as well as the synopsis for a related talk given at an OECD conference in Paris in December of the same year.
    - Child and Elderly Care OECD Tables and Graphs to Make, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      Materials supporting an OECD report (SMC, 1997, Childcare and Elderly Care: What Opportunities for Women?) and talks (in R 4-28) along with a cover letter to the OECD.
    - Lecture/New Urban Forms, Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
      Figures (paper and overhead) and notes for a lecture on new urban forms. It is not clear if this is a class lecture or not, although the files was in with other, more academic, material. Also notable is a generic letter from the Project Director of the Congressional Office of Technology Assessment, that came along with a report. The letter, dated October 1995, is of particular interest because it acknowledges that the office is being shut down.
    - Jordan Paper; Workshop, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      Contains paper and correspondence relating to a workshop in Jordan to discuss "Jordan's Policies and Strategies in Audiovisual Media" and the industries that produce them.
    - Jordan Study, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      Drafts and correspondence relating to the study of Jordan's media industry
    - Fortress City/New Stuff, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      Materials relating to "The Fortress City: Privatized Spaces, Consumer Citizenship" a chapter in Ash Amin's edited book, Post-Fordism, including responses to queries on a text
    - Retail "Consumption Production" Redone, 1995-08 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      Materials and correspondence around the remaking of a faulty table that was schedued to be included SMC's book chapter "The Production of Consumption" appearing in Wrigley and Lowe's edited volume Retailing, Consumption and Capital.
    - Double Jeopardy, Undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
      Typescript of the "Double Jeopardy" paper about rural women published through the Southwest Institute for Research on Women
    - Regional Differences/Contingency, Undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
      Materials related to regional differences in contingent labor. Many of the notes are have a heading that indicates they are for the "Buffalo Paper"
    - Contingency-International Comparisons, Undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
      A reading and notes related to quesitons of contingency. Four pages of handwritten notes are titled 'For critique of neoclassical approach to the problem.' Two pages are notes from an OECD study.
    - Contingency: Reading Notes Misc., Undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
      Handwritten notes on contingency
    - Peak Times/Slack Time, Undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
      Materials, including notes, relating to the idea of corporate behavior in peak times and slack times
    - Contingent Labor References, Undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
      Bibliographical materials, including notes, relating to the issue of contingent labor
    - Contingent Labor Market, Undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
      Contains outline entitled "Contractual Labor Market Paper" and related materials
    - Notes for Policy Paper, Undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
      Pages of handwritten notes
    - Food Industry Study-for Article, Undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
      Contains material related to failed application (with Ned Rightor) for a grant from the Russell Sage Foundation to study labor in the food retailing industries.
    - TV in Developing…Proposal, Undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
      Draft proposal for a study of television in Jordan, Malaysia, and Indonesia and related materials
    - Book Prospectus: Contingency, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      Materials, including a draft prospectus and comments from SMC colleagues, for a book entited 'Working at the Margins: The Meaning of Flexible Labor in the Changing Economy'
    - Logistics/Retail Proposal, Undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
      Notes for a paper or book on logistics, also includes a copy of the proposal to Russell Sage for the retail food project
    - Silicon Valley Critique/Overheads, Undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
      Overheads and materials relating to talk on Silicon Valley
    - Economic Impact of Higher Ed, 2007-05-10 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      Printout of slides with SMC notes for a talk on Cornell's economic impact on Tompkins County, as well as a couple of related articles
    - The Learning Region, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      Notes, a draft of Chapter Seven of Remaking Regional Economies, and related materials.
    - Limits to the Knowledge Economy, Undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
      Slides for a talk and a four page outline, labeled "Preliminary"
    - Perry Paper, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      A preliminary abstract and correspondence relating to a paper written for a special issue of the journal 'Built Environment' edited by Beth Perry and Tim May---note that other materials for this paper are in Box 3, folders 50 and 51
    - OECD HEI Studies Overall, 2009-09-10-2009-09-11 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      Notes and materials from an OECD meeting "Reviews of Higher Education in Regional and City Development: Roundtable Meeting for Cities and Regions" for whilch SMC served as a discussant.
    - Biotech Clusters in Catalonia, Undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
      Notes on Biotech and Life Sciences Cluster Development in Catalonia
    - Media Book Bib/Proposal, Undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
      In box labeled "Media Files for Book": contains notes and few materials, but neither bib nor proposal
    - Building the Future Slides, Undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
      In box labeled "Media Files for Book"
    - McDonald/Wasko Book Article, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Unfiled Media Materials 2, 2004-2007 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - McKinlay Article, 2001-2007 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Unfiled Media Materials 3, Undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Regional Inequality, Undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
      Accumulated near materials near file on inequality
    - OECD HEI Sonora Study, 2009-2013 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Notes, slides, and materials relating to OECD Higher Education in City and Regional Development study of Sonora, Mexico on which SMC was a coauthor. The study can be found at https://web.archive.org/web/20160815130127/http://www.oecd.org/edu/imhe/109255%20Cover%20+%20body%20opt.pdf
    - For Wal-Mart Article, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Notes and related materials about Wal-Mart
    - Wal-Mart Update, Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Materials, notes, edited paper drafts relating to SMC work on Wal-Mart
    - Outsourcing Study, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Media Industry Reports 05, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Industry Report, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Storper/Christopherson Haynes Foundatin Study, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - New Media Study Key Docs 1/2, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - New Media Study Key Docs 2/2, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Big Squeeze, October 1985 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Rockefeller Proposal, 2005-2006 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Contemporary Film Anthology, 2005-2006 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Munich Film Cluster Article, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - NYFTCI Final Report, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Unfiled Media Materials, Undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
      In box labeled "Media Files for Book": Unfiled notes, page proofs, etc. on media projects
    - Media Hub Proposal, 2004-2006 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Migrating Media Paper, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      In box labeled "Media Files for Book": Materials for paper presented at the Migrating Media Conference in Toronto, Sept, 2007
    - Working the Creative Economy, Undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Media Work, Undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - New Forms of Exclusion, Undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous 2, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - JPER Paper, 2006-2007 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      Includes correspondence with Jennifer Clark
    - GL Presentation, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      Slides and notes
    - OECD Mtg Seville February, Undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - RRPC Talk, 2014 (Box 8, Folder 25)
      Notes and correspondence related to Rochester Regional Photonics Cluster event
    - Norfolk Talk, 2012-06-04-2012-06-05 (Box 8, Folder 26)
      Talk and itinerary--meeting with local developers and economic developers
    - RSA Critical Planning Resilience, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Syracuse, 2012-06-20 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      SMC panelist at conference on New York's new fiscal reality
    - Miscellaneous 3, Undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
      Documents and notes related to, among other things, transportation of gas
    - National Space Economy Trucking Lecture, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Colloquium Talk Notes, Undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Natural Gas Drilling and the NY Economy, Undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - CRP Workshop Webinar/Webinar Prep, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Green/Phoenix Presentation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - NYSAC Presentation 5/15, 2007-05-15 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Talk on hidden trends in upstate economy for Southern Tier Regional Economic Development meeting
    - Power in Firm Nets, Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Talk materials on power in firm networks
    - Creative Workers Talk, Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Media Overheads for London, Undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Talk on media work and the new economy
    - Wal-Mart Overheads/Talk, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Back to the Future Talk, Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
      Notes and copy of overheads for talk on regulatory change and the new geography of media
    - London New Media Presentation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Triad Presentation, October 07, 2007-10-16 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      Panel, discuss upstate NY economic development
    - WCNY Appearance, 2008-02 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      SMC participated in a panel on WCNY
    - Presentation Upstate, 2005-10-06 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      Panel on economic sustainability put on by Cornell Cooperative Extension
    - Dot.com Bust Paper/Presentation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Toronto Geoforum/Book Case Presentation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Conference Powerpoint, Undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
      Powerpoint for a presentation on economic development in Rochester
    - Power in Networks Presentation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
      Presentation based on work with Jennifer Clark
    - Role of Power Talk, Undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
      Presentation based on work with Jennifer Clark, notes say for a talk in Newcastle
    - Bousfield Lecture, Undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
      Given at University of Toronto some time between 2007 and 2009
    - Triad/Funders Presentation 10/16, 2007-10-16 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      See also Research Box 6 Folder 23
    - WCNY Presentation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
      A different appearance than Box 6 Folder 24
    - Clusters Lecture Rochester from Conference, Undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - "Rules as"/Talk, Undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
      Material and overhead for both course lecture (417/517) and talk
    - Rethinking Regional Innovation Talk, Undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Global Paper Revisions, Undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
      Lots of handwritten notes
    - Tompkins County United Way Presentation Also for 448, 2005-02-10 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - WHCU Interview, 2008-09 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Casey/Chapple Big Ideas Project, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 30)
      Project on Big Ideas organized by Karen Chapple at Berkeley and Robert Giloth at the Annie E. Casey Foundation
    - Chapple/Giloth ppr Interviews, Undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
      Title is somewhat aspirational
    - New Media Presentations Graphics, Undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
      Possibly for a presentation to the Sloan Foundation involving Rose Batt and Ned Rightor as well as for the IRRA Meetings Jan 4-6, 2002
    - Labor Standards Overheads, Undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Albany Paper Notes, Undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
      Notes and overheads for talk, 'Creative Economy Strategies for Small and Medium Size Cities: Options for New York'
    - GLS Presentations, Undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
      Materials including draft paper for a talk: Neither Global Nor Standard: Corporate Strategies in the New Era of Labor Standards
    - Excellus Presentation, 2006-05-18 (Box 9, Folder 36)
      SMC talk to Governing Board of Excellus BlueCross BlueShield about the upstate economy
    - Ag Tech Park Talk, Undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Ag Tech/Geneva Talk, Undated (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Bonn New Media Talk, Undated (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Upstate New York Presentation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - United Way Presentation, 2005-02-10 (Box 9, Folder 41)
      Transparencies related to Box 6 Folder 38
    - Planners Network Talk, 2001-06-23 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - February Stowe Conference, Undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Thinking Regionally Presentation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Brookings Manufacturing, 2003-03 (Box 9, Folder 45)
      Correspondence from Rolf Pendall about continuing work with Brookings on a project--SMC note about using material for talk to United Way of Tompkins County
    - Knowledge Economy Notes, 2006-2010 (Box 9, Folder 46)
      Contains a lot of material about knowledge economy, university-led economic development and biotech.
    - Economic Development Articles Reports, 1995-1998 (Box 9, Folder 47)
      Includes piece on Green Bay Packers with SMC notes
    - Christopherson/Talk Ideas, Undated (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Culture Trade Global, Undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
      A couple of pieces and notes
    - Study Data, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Data collected during Photonics study
    - Kauffman Proposal, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Manufacturing Surge Contacts Data References, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Notes on Helper/Wial and related, Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Port of Albany, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Energy Planning Transitions, Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Off Shore (sic) Wind, Undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Storper B[oo]k R[e]v[ie]w, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Oxford Handbook/CJRES New Inequality, Undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Smart Cities, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      SMC notes on the topic, along with some correspondence within AAP regarding the topic.
    - Financialization, Undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
      smc notes
    - Food Proposal/Industry Sage, 1998-05-11 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      Proposal letter to Russell Sage Foundation
    - RIG [Rockefeller Institute of Government]/NYS Project, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Start Up New York, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Paper with Sudeshna, Undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
      Notes for a paper to be coauthored with Sudeshna Mitra
    - NSF Sustain Prop, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      Materials related to an NSF request for proposals on sustainable urbanism, floated through Cornell's Atkinson Center.
    - GLC [Great Lakes Commission] Project Smmr 2014, Summer 2014 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Oil Train Risks, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Talk Ideas, Undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Ideas for Blogs/Talks, Undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Marcellus Shale Contacts and Press Accounts, 2010-2011 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Shale Gas Presentation, 2013-2014 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Marcellus Presentations and Interviews, 2010-2015 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Sea Grant Webinar, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Great Lakes Funding Webinar, Undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Crude Transport Talk for ACSP, Undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Ithaca College Marcellus February 6, 2012, 2012-02-06 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - PA ? TCCOC presentation, June 2011, 2011-06 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - DC US-UK Wrkshp Nov, 2015-11-05-2015-11-06 (Box 10, Folder 30)
      NSF-sponsored US-UK workshop on environmental impacts of hydrolic facturing
    - Chicago GRT LKS October 20-22, 2015-10-20-2015-10-22 (Box 10, Folder 31)
      Conference on shpment of crude oil
    - Cleveland 11-11-12, 2015-11-12 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      Advancing Equity Planning conference, tied to book organized to celebrate Norm Krumholz's 90th birthday--SMC chaired a session
    - GLLC [Great Lakes Legislative Caucus] 9 25-26, 2015-09-25-2015-09-26 (Box 10, Folder 33)
      SMC talks about shipment of crude oil
    - Oxford 8-19-23, 2015-08-19-2015-08-23 (Box 10, Folder 34)
      International Conference of Economic Geography, plus meetings about the Handbook of Economic Geography
    - Manchester, 2015-11-2015-12 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Marcellus Presentation UK, Undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Oxford/Newcastle Marcellus Talks, Undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Washington DC Presentation, June 25th, 2012-06-25 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Notes for Symposium on Fainstein's 'The City Builders', 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Economic resilience, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Economic resilience/Book idea, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Articles requested, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Articles for Geo Forum, 2003-2004 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Cultural policy article, 2002-2003 (Box 10, Folder 44)